Guide to the Monroe Wheeler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Museum of Modern Art Records (MOMA), 1929-88; Series IX; 22.89; (56 boxes)
  - OTHER OFFICE FILES
    - Reproductions of artists' works
      - Boccioni, Umberto, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2942)
      - Bonnard, Pierre, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2943)
      - Braque, Georges, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2944)
      - Cézanne, Paul, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2945)
      - Chagall, Marc, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2946)
      - De Chirico, Giorgio, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2947)
      - Dali, Salvador, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2948)
      - Delaunay, Robert, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2949)
      - Derain, André (Box 234, Folder 2950)
      - Doesburg, Théo van, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2951)
      - Duchamp, Marcel, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2952)
      - Dufy, Raoul, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2953)
      - Ensor, James, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2954)
      - Ernst, Max, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2955)
      - Feininger, Lyonel, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2956)
      - Gauguin, Paul, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2957)
      - Gogh, Vincent van, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2958)
      - Gris, Juan, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2959)
      - Jawlensy, Alexej von, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2960)
      - Kandinsky, Wassily (Box 234, Folder 2961)
      - Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2962)
      - Klee, Paul, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2963)
      - Kokoschka, Oskar, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2964)
      - Léger, Fernand (Box 234, Folder 2965)
      - Lissitzky, El, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2966)
      - Magritte, René, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2967)
      - Malevich, Kasimir, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2968)
      - Matisse, Henri, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2969)
      - Miró, Joan, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2970)
      - Modigliani, Amedeo, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2971)
      - Mondrian, Piet (Box 234, Folder 2972)
      - Monet, Claude, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2973)
      - Morandi, Claude (Box 234, Folder 2974)
      - Munch, Edvard, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2975)
      - Nolde, Emil, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2976)
      - Picasso, Pablo, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2977)
      - Redon, Odilon, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2978)
      - Rouault, Georges, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2979)
      - Rousseau, Henri, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2980)
      - Schwitters, Kurt, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2981)
      - Seurat, Georges, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2982)
      - Severini, Gino, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2983)
      - Soutine, Chaim, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2984)
      - Tanguy, Yves, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2985)
      - Utrillo, Maurice, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2986)
      - Vlaminck, Maurice de, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2987)
      - Vuillard, Edouard, n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2988)
      - "Miscellaneous", n.d. (Box 234, Folder 2989)
    - People
      - Apraxine, Pierre, 1971 (Box 235, Folder 2990)
      - Barr, Alfred H. Barr, Jr., 1961-66 (Box 235, Folder 2991)
      - Burden, William A. M., 1958-66 (Box 235, Folder 2992)
      - Clark, Eleanor, 1965 (Box 235, Folder 2993)
      - d'Harnoncourt, René, ca. 1952-68 (Box 235, Folder 2994)
      - Richard Koch, 1960-66 (Box 235, Folder 2995)
      - McBride, Henry ["from Max Miltzlaff"], 1966 (Box 235, Folder 2996)
      - Marx, Samuel and Florene Schoenborn, 1952-67 (Box 235, Folder 2997)
      - Rockefeller, Blanchette, 1960-64 (Box 235, Folder 2998)
      - Rockefeller, David, 1960, 1965 (Box 235, Folder 2999)
      - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1954-68 (Box 235, Folder 3000)
      - Soby, James Thrall, "Laugh File", 1942-64 (Box 235, Folder 3001)
      - Soby, James Thrall, 1942-64 (Box 235, Folder 3002)
      - Stevens, Wallace, 1921-65 (Box 235, Folder 3003)
      - Wescott, Glenway, 1962 Oct 2 (Box 235, Folder 3004)
    - Travel
      - "M. Wheeler's Asian Trip 1959" (Box 235, Folder 3005)
      - "Belgium", 1974 May 10 (Box 235, Folder 3006)
      - "Brazil", 1961 (Box 235, Folder 3007)
      - "Delhi", 1954 (Box 235, Folder 3008)
      - "MW - Europe", 1963-64 (Box 235, Folder 3009)
      - "Agenda for Europe - Spring 1950", 1949-50 (Box 235, Folder 3010)
      - "M.W. Trip to Europe - 1952" (Box 235, Folder 3011)
      - "MW: Europe Trip 1958", 1957-58 (Box 235, Folder 3012)
      - "Europe 1962" (Box 235, Folder 3013)
        empty
      - "Europe 1963" (Box 235, Folder 3014)
      - "Europe 1965", 1965 Sep (Box 235, Folder 3015-3016)
      - "France", 1970 (Box 236, Folder 3017)
      - "India", 1955-87 (Box 236, Folder 3018-3020)
      - [India], 1948-54 (Box 236, Folder 3021)
      - "India - Personal", 1949-54 (Box 236, Folder 3022)
      - "Indonesia" (Box 236, Folder 3023)
      - "Japan", 1974 May (Box 236, Folder 3024)
      - "Proposed Trip - Japan - 1959" (Box 236, Folder 3025)
      - "Latin America" '69", 1969 (Box 236, Folder 3026)
      - "London 1965 - December", 1965-66 (Box 236, Folder 3027)
      - "London 1966", 1966-67 (Box 236, Folder 3028)
      - "Melbourne", 1968 Aug (Box 236, Folder 3029)
      - "Mexico", 1971-72 (Box 236, Folder 3030)
      - "Paris - London: October 1962" (Box 236, Folder 3031)
      - "South America", 1968 (Box 236, Folder 3032)
      - "South American Trip: Arrangements, Names of Contacts", 1953-56 (Box 236, Folder 3033)
      - "Texas", 1971-73 (Box 237, Folder 3034)
      - "Monroe Wheeler: 1958 Trip" [Europe] (Box 237, Folder 3035)
      - "MW Travel Tickets", 1965-67 (Box 237, Folder 3036)
      - "Travel", 1972, 1976 (Box 237, Folder 3037)
    - MW Organizational Affiliations
      - American Federation of Arts: "Latin-American Art", 1972 Jul 13 (Box 237, Folder 3038)
      - Asia Society: "Asia Society Program", 1968 (Box 237, Folder 3039)
      - Asia Society: "Asia", 1959 (Box 237, Folder 3040)
      - Asia Society: "Balinese Art Exhibition", 1958-59 (Box 237, Folder 3041)
      - Asia Society: "Paintings from India", 1954-58 (Box 237, Folder 3042)
      - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1982 (Box 237, Folder 3043)
      - Center for Inter-American Relations: "Addresses for 'Looking South'", 1972 May (Box 237, Folder 3044)
      - Center for Inter-American Relations: "Visual Arts", 1984 (Box 237, Folder 3045)
      - Grolier Club, 1939-66 (Box 237, Folder 3046-3047)
      - International Center for the Typographic Arts, 1964 Dec 31 (Box 237, Folder 3048)
      - International Council of Museums, 1960 May 23 (Box 237, Folder 3049)
      - Keats Shelley Association of America, 1961-66 (Box 237, Folder 3050)
      - Metropolitan Opera National Council, 1965 (Box 237, Folder 3051)
      - Mrs. Albert Lasker Foundation, 1966-67 (Box 237, Folder 3052)
      - New York Genealogical & Biographical Society, 1959-67 (Box 237, Folder 3053)
      - Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, 1941 Sep 15 (Box 237, Folder 3054)
      - Public Education Association, 1963-64 (Box 237, Folder 3055)
      - Typophiles, 1960-73 (Box 237, Folder 3056)
    - Various Subjects
      - "Art", 1960-79 (Box 238, Folder 3057)
      - "Harry B. Lee: Art & Psychology", 1947, 1953 (Box 238, Folder 3058)
      - "Attendance - Membership, Sales", 1967-69 (Box 238, Folder 3059)
      - "Book Listings", 1960 (Box 238, Folder 3060)
      - "Drawings and Prints", 1942, n.d. (Box 238, Folder 3061)
      - "Film Library", 1967 (Box 238, Folder 3062)
      - "Fund Raising", 1970-78 (Box 238, Folder 3063-3064)
      - "Hold for Later Action", 1948-55 (Box 238, Folder 3065)
        Includes typescript of lecture by Norman Kelman, "Notes on Parent-Child Relations
      - "Ideas", n.d. (Box 238, Folder 3066)
      - "Index to Monroe Wheeler's Files", [1959?] (Box 238, Folder 3067)
      - Latin-American Art, 1968 Sep 15 (Box 238, Folder 3068)
      - "Mr. Monroe Wheeler", 1974-75 (Box 238, Folder 3069)
      - "MOMA Budget Log", 1972-73 (Box 238, Folder 3070)
      - Museum Director's Conference, 1972 (Box 238, Folder 3071)
      - "MW Biography", 1961-66 (Box 238, Folder 3072)
      - "MW file", 1967 Nov 21 (Box 238, Folder 3073)
      - "New York", 1963 (Box 238, Folder 3074)
      - "Portraits", 1954-74, n.d. (Box 238, Folder 3075)
      - "Prix International Guggenheim, 1960", 1960, 1963 (Box 238, Folder 3076)
      - "Puerto Rico Loans: N. A. R.", 1959 (Box 238, Folder 3077)
      - "Texas", 1972-73 (Box 238, Folder 3078)
      - "Walter Prendergrast's Velvet Brush-Off Letters", 1941 (Box 238, Folder 3079)
  - OTHER MATERIAL
    - Agenda re: Latin American Museum meeting (Box 239, Folder 3080)
    - Agreement between MOMA, the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and the Whitney Museum of Art, proof, 1947 Jul 10 (Box 239, Folder 3081)
    - American Association of Museums annual meeting brochure, 1972 (Box 239, Folder 3082)
    - Application for employment: Douglas Charles Lee, 1968 Feb 6 (Box 239, Folder 3083)
    - Auction house brochures and listings, ca. 1970s-80s (Box 239, Folder 3084)
    - Brochure: Museology program, University of Toronto, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 3085)
    - Brochure from Theodore L. Shaw for publication attacking the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1970 (Box 239, Folder 3086)
    - Budget for performance of "Facade", ca. 1949 (Box 239, Folder 3087)
      with invitation
    - Bylaws, 1946-78 (Box 239, Folder 3088)
    - Change of address notice: MW, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 3089)
    - Committee on Art Education conference report: "A Search for a Basic Philosophy", 1947 Apr (Box 239, Folder 3090)
    - "Drawings and Prints: Buenos Aires", 1968 May (Box 239, Folder 3091)
    - Event seating lists, 1946-85, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 3092-3095)
    - Festival of India list of programs, 1985 (Box 239, Folder 3096)
    - 50th Anniversary information packet, 1979 (Box 239, Folder 3097)
    - "Graphic Art in Monroe's portable print box", n.d. (Box 239, Folder 3098)
    - Iranian Institute Supper Conference program, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 3099)
    - Lists of artworks, 1965, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 3100)
    - Lists of meetings, 1969 Jul (Box 239, Folder 3101)
    - Lists of museums in Sydney, Australia, 1968 (Box 239, Folder 3102)
    - Lists of works on paper in MOMA collections, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 3103)
    - [Map of MOMA collections?], n.d. (Box 239, Folder 3104)
    - Material from other museums and galleries
      - Catalog: "Third Triennale: India", 1975 (Box 239, Folder 3105)
        MW on jury
      - Bulletins, catalogs, checklists and tickets, ca. 1950s-80s (Box 239, Folder 3106-3107)
      - Bulletins, catalogs, checklists and tickets, ca. 1950s-80s (Box 240, Folder 3108)
      - Newsletters, 1967-85, n.d. (Box 240, Folder 3109)
      - News releases and brochures, ca. 1960s-80s (Box 240, Folder 3110-3111)
    - Membership card: Paul Cadmus, 1979-80 (Box 240, Folder 3112)
    - Memo re: exchange of art between MOMA and Walter P. Chrysler (Box 240, Folder 3113)
    - "Names and addresses in London and Bath" (Box 240, Folder 3114)
    - Nametag: Monroe Wheeler, n.d. (Box 240, Folder 3115)
    - Notes re: Picasso paintings, ca. 1963-67 (Box 240, Folder 3116)
    - Notes re: reinstallation of the P & S Collection, n.d. (Box 240, Folder 3117)
    - Packet of MOMA material, 1978 (Box 240, Folder 3118)
    - Passes, n.d. (Box 240, Folder 3119)
    - Registrar's cards [blank], n.d. (Box 240, Folder 3120)
    - Registrar's cards (with other notecards) on artists and loans (Box 241, Folder 3121-3126)
    - Review of Matisse exhibition by Hilton Kramer, wire report, 1978 Oct 30 (Box 242, Folder 3127)
    - "The Nelson Rockefeller Collection, Inc." [reproduction catalog], 1982 (Box 242, Folder 3128)
    - Schedule of events for reopening of MOMA, 1984 Feb 8 (Box 242, Folder 3129)
    - Scrapbook: re: MW's career and MOMA, ca. 1938-50
      Includes photographs of opening of various exhibitions
    - Staff booklet, 1969, 1972 (Box 242, Folder 3130)
    - Staff lists, ca. 1960s-80s (Box 242, Folder 3131)
    - Stationery
      - Memo Forms, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3132)
      - MOMA schedule sheets, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3133)
      - Letterhead stationery, 1961, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3134)
    - Travel itineraries, 1953-71, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3135)
    - Visitors lists, 1961, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3136)
    - Visits to private collections, lists of artworks, 1961-82, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3137)
    - Notes
      - Memo pad: Marge's meals, Paul Strand" (Box 242, Folder 3138)
      - Memo pad, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3139)
      - Memo pad, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3140)
      - Notebook binder, ca. 1944-70 (Box 242, Folder 3141)
      - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 3142)
      - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 243, Folder 3143-3153)
  - INTERNATIONAL COUNCIL OF MOMA
    - Annual reports, 1971-81 (Box 244, Folder 3154-3155)
    - Brochures, [1979?], n.d. (Box 244, Folder 3156)
    - Dinner at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, seating list, 1969 Nov 10 (Box 244, Folder 3157)
    - "Exhibitions circulated by the International Council" list, 1958 Jul (Box 244, Folder 3158)
    - Exhibitions list, 1984 Apr 6 (Box 244, Folder 3159)
    - Financial reports, 1968-81 (Box 244, Folder 3160)
    - Information sheets, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 3161)
    - Lecture/speech given in Berlin [by MW?], drafts (in English and German) (Box 244, Folder 3162)
    - "Letter from Australia" by Shirley Hazzard, photocopy of article, 1977 Jan 3 (Box 244, Folder 3163)
    - Lists of individual prospects (Box 244, Folder 3164)
    - Meeting materials, 1967 (Box 244, Folder 3165)
    - Meeting materials, 1968 (Box 244, Folder 3166)
    - Meeting materials, 1969 (Box 244, Folder 3167)
    - Meeting materials, 1970 (Box 244, Folder 3168)
    - Meeting materials, 1971 (Box 245, Folder 3169-3170)
    - Meeting materials, 1972 (Box 245, Folder 3171)
    - Meeting materials, 1973 (Box 245, Folder 3172-3173)
    - Meeting materials, 1974 (Box 245, Folder 3174)
    - Meeting materials, 1975 (Box 245, Folder 3175)
    - Meeting materials, 1975 (Box 246, Folder 3176)
    - Meeting materials, 1976 (Box 246, Folder 3177)
    - Meeting materials, 1977 (Box 246, Folder 3178-3179)
    - Meeting materials, 1978 (Box 246, Folder 3180-3181)
    - Meeting materials, 1979 (Box 246, Folder 3182-3183)
    - Meeting materials, 1980 (Box 246, Folder 3184)
    - Meeting materials, 1981 (Box 246, Folder 3185)
    - Meeting materials, 1982 (Box 246, Folder 3186-3187)
    - Meeting materials, 1983 (Box 246, Folder 3188-3189)
    - Meeting materials, 1984 (Box 246, Folder 3190)
    - Meeting materials, 1984 (Box 247, Folder 3191)
    - Meeting materials, 1985 (Box 247, Folder 3192-3193)
    - Meeting materials, 1986 (Box 247, Folder 3194-3198)
    - Meeting materials, 1988 (Box 247, Folder 3199)
    - Meeting materials, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 3200)
    - Meeting minutes (boards and subcommittees), 1968-82 (Box 247, Folder 3201-3203)
    - Membership lists, 1968-87 (Box 248, Folder 3204-3206)
    - Memos and letters, 1967-88, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 3207)
    - Nametag: MW, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 3208)
    - Newsletters, 1977-82 (Box 248, Folder 3209)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 3210)
    - Stationery, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 3211)
  - ROCKEFELLER MISSION TO LATIN AMERICA
    - Briefing background material: Argentina, 1969 (Box 249, Folder 3212)
    - Briefing background material: Barbados, 1969 (Box 249, Folder 3213)
    - Briefing background material: Columbia, 1969 (Box 249, Folder 3214)
    - Briefing background material: Dominican Republic, 1969 (Box 249, Folder 3215)
    - Briefing background material: Guyana, 1969 (Box 249, Folder 3216)
    - Briefing background material: Haiti, 1969 (Box 249, Folder 3217)
    - Briefing background material: Jamaica, 1969 (Box 249, Folder 3218)
    - Briefing background material: Paraguay, 1969 (Box 250, Folder 3219-3220)
    - Briefing background material: Trinidad and Tobago, 1969 (Box 250, Folder 3221)
    - Briefing background material: Uruguay, 1969 (Box 250, Folder 3222)
    - Background information, loose: Trinidad and Tobago, 1968-69 (Box 250, Folder 3223)
    - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 250, Folder 3224)
    - Clippings, 1969 (Box 250, Folder 3225)
    - Correspondence and memos, 1969 (Box 250, Folder 3226)
    - "Dados biographicos dos membros da Missao Rockefeller": Monroe Wheeler, 1969 May (Box 250, Folder 3227)
    - Guest list, reception in Columbia, 1969 May 28 (Box 250, Folder 3228)
    - Information packet, biographical sketches of mission members, 1969 (Box 250, Folder 3229)
    - Information packet: Brasilia, Brazil, 1969 Jun (Box 251, Folder 3230)
    - Information packet: Quito, Ecuador, 1969 May (Box 251, Folder 3231)
    - Information packet: El Minuto de Dios, Bogota, Columbia, 1968-69 (Box 251, Folder 3232)
    - Information packet: Paraguay, 1965-69 (Box 251, Folder 3233-3234)
    - Lists of people and room assignments, 1969 (Box 251, Folder 3235)
    - Menu, 1969 (Box 251, Folder 3236)
    - Note re: Palace of the Dawn, 1965 Oct (Box 251, Folder 3237)
    - Notebook: "Schedule", 1969 (Box 251, Folder 3238)
    - Notebooks: "Trip III & IV", 1969 (Box 252, Folder 3239-3240)
    - Notebook: "Trip IV", 1969 (Box 252, Folder 3241)
    - Notebook pages: loose pages, 1969 (Box 253, Folder 3242-3243)
    - Notepad, n.d. (Box 253, Folder 3244)
    - Notes, 1969 (Box 253, Folder 3245)
    - Place cards (with notes), n.d. (Box 253, Folder 3246)
    - Presentation to Dinner of Board of Directors, the Equitable Life Assurance Society - by Clifton R. Wharton, Jr., 1969 Jul 16 (Box 253, Folder 3247)
    - Presidential address re: Rockefeller mission, 1969 (Box 253, Folder 3248)
    - Press conference transcripts, 1969 (Box 253, Folder 3249)
    - Program: music recital, 1969 May 31 (Box 253, Folder 3250)
    - Report on "Cultural Affairs" by MW, notebook with drafts, 1969 Jun (Box 253, Folder 3251)
    - Report on "Cultural Affairs" by MW, printed version, n.d. (Box 253, Folder 3252)
    - [Report on Latin America by MW?], draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 253, Folder 3253)
    - Reports from mission members, 1969 (Box 253, Folder 3254-3255)
    - NAR Testimony before subcommittee of Inter-American Affairs, 1969 Nov 12 (Box 253, Folder 3256)
    - Schedules, 1969 (Box 253, Folder 3257-3258)
    - Statutes of the Centro Cultural Paraguayo-Americano, 1968 Aug 23 (Box 253, Folder 3259)
    - Transcript of remarks by NAR at the National Conference of UPI Editors & Publishers, 1969 Oct 7 (Box 253, Folder 3260)
- Objects, 1920s-1975; Series X; 4; (6 boxes)
  Series X, Objects, is arranged alphabetically and by object dimensions.
  - Advertising ruler: "glace polie, marque A.M.G.E.C.", n.d. (Box 254, Folder 3261)
  - Letter openers (2): Museum of Modern Art, n.d. (Box 254, Folder 3262)
  - Necktie, green rayon with pink roses, given as present from Glenway Wescott to Monroe Wheeler, with note, in box decorated with manuscript pages, 1936 (Box 254, Folder 3263)
  - Necktie, pink polyester, with buttons: peace sign and "International Exhibition of Modern Art, New York, 1913" [reproduction] (Box 254, Folder 3264)
  - Needlepoint work for pin cushion, executed by George Platt Lynes after design by Klee, given as Christmas card to Monroe Wheeler, 1944 (Box 254, Folder 3265)
  - Plaque: University of Maryland President's Club: "Presented to Monroe Wheeler for outstanding contributions to... ongoing programs.. .", 1975 Fall (Box 254, Folder 3266)
  - Printing plate, copper, engraved: "Mr. Monroe Wheeler", n.d. (Box 254, Folder 3267)
  - Candlestick base [?] or printer's tool[?] (Box 255, Folder 3268)
  - Certificate naming Monroe Wheeler as Chevalier in the Legion of Honor, 1951 Mar 20 (Box 256, Folder 3269)
    In cylindrical carrying case, finished in orange velvet
  - Legion of Honor medal, ca. 1951 (Box 256, Folder 3270)
    In custom case
  - Legion of Honor ribbon fragments, ca. 1951 (Box 256, Folder 3271)
  - "North African Headgear" - 5 knit caps worn by Monroe Wheeler, ca. 1930s-40s (Box 256, Folder 3272-3276)
  - Woven fabric belt, red, n.d. (Box 256, Folder 3277)
  - Embossing tools (3), n.d. (Box 257, Folder 3278-3280)
    Reading: "Monroe Wheeler"; "HAY-MEADOWS ROSEMONT NEW JERSEY"; and "FROM THE TYPOGRAPHICAL LIBRARY OF MONROE WHEELER"
  - Seeds: Spider flower; and two unidentified types [from West Indies] (Box 258, Folder 3281)
  - Seeds: "Peg's Hollyhock seed"; and Mardi Gras Lily seed (Box 258, Folder 3282)
  - Seeds: Hemlock cones from Vanderbilt estate, Hyde Park; and Mouton fir cones (Box 258, Folder 3283)
  - Top hat owned by Glenway Wescott, in original box from Hilhouse & Co., London, ca. 1920s (Box 259, Folder 3284)
- Oversize, 1920s-1975; 8.2; (7 boxes)
  - "The Painter who Inspired Hollywood", printed version, The Sunday Times Magazine (in Series II), 1968 Feb 18 (Box 260, Folder 3285)
  - Untitled notebook (in Series III), ca. 1957-69 (Box 260, Folder 3286)
  - Annotated printed items (in Series III), ca. 1946-85 (Box 260, Folder 3287)
  - Scrapbook: re: Artists and exhibitions (in Series III), ca. 1948-55 (Box 261, Folder 3288)
  - Scrapbook: re: MW's career and MOMA (in Series IX), ca. 1938-50 (Box 261, Folder 3289)
  - Calder, Alexander, proof of designs for Christmas cards (in Series VI) (Box 262, Folder 3290)
  - Commercial reproductions of artworks (in Series VI), n.d. (Box 262, Folder 3291)
  - Images clipped from publications (in Series VI), ca. 1950s-80s (Box 262, Folder 3292)
  - Notecards (in Series VI), n.d. (Box 262, Folder 3293)
  - Postcards: art & travel views and scenes (in Series VI) (Box 262, Folder 3294)
  - Architecture (in Series VII), ca. 1947-87 (Box 263, Folder 3295)
  - Art: exhibitions and acquisitions (in Series VII), ca. 1941-85 (Box 263, Folder 3296)
  - Art: general (in Series VII), ca. 1945-93 (Box 263, Folder 3297)
  - Art: history (in Series VII), ca. 1957-83 (Box 263, Folder 3298)
  - Art: images (in Series VII), ca. 1941-83 (Box 263, Folder 3299)
  - Art: MOMA (in Series VII), ca. 1931-84 (Box 263, Folder 3300)
  - Art: People (in Series VII), ca. 1936-86 (Box 263, Folder 3301)
  - Book reviews (in Series VII), ca. 1940-90 (Box 264, Folder 3302)
  - Current Events (in Series VII), ca. 1940-86 (Box 264, Folder 3303)
  - Dance and theater (in Series VII), ca. 1946-85 (Box 264, Folder 3304)
  - Essays and articles (in Series VII), ca. 1954-85 (Box 264, Folder 3305)
  - Natural Sciences (in Series VII), ca. 1948-83 (Box 264, Folder 3306)
  - People (in Series VII), ca. 1941-87 (Box 265, Folder 3307)
  - Travel (in Series VII), ca. 1937-86 (Box 265, Folder 3308-3311)
  - "Turner: Painter of Air, Fire, and Water", article, printed version, Look (in Series IX), 1966 Apr 5 (Box 266, Folder 3312)
  - Notebook of descriptive texts by LM on her paintings (in Series IX), 1974 (Box 266, Folder 3313)
  - Color art reproductions proofs for unidentified publications (in Series IX), n.d. (Box 266, Folder 3314)
  - Artists' Files: Utrillo, Maurice (in Series IX), 1939-52 (Box 266, Folder 3315)